Johns Hopkins University - Gain the expertise you need in the data revol



Lawrence McNeil · 3rd

Dean - College of Business at Bowie State University

Bowie, Maryland, United States · 493 connections · Contact info

Bowie State Univ

HOWARD

Connect

Howard Universit

Message

Highlights



1 Mutual Group

You and Lawrence are both in Research, Methodology, and Statistics in the Social Sciences

About

Experienced administrator with a successful history of working in the higher education industry. Skilled International Economics, Educational Technologies, Leadership, Student Development, Data Analysis, a Statistics. Education professional with a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Economics from Howard Univer

Activity

500 followers



What an outstanding achievement! Congratulations!

Lawrence commented



On Monday, we welcome all the new students to our beautiful campus at...

Lawrence shared this
13 Reactions



Congrats on earning this ce Tyler Hayes! Looking forwa

Lawrence commented



The Sweet Setup has excell productivity courses. Mainl

Lawrence shared this 3 Reactions

Experience



Dean - College of Business

Bowie State University · Full-time Jan 2020 – Present · 8 mos Bowie, Maryland



Associate Professor of Economics / Professional Development Program Coordinator

Prairie View A&M University

Aug 2008 – Jan 2020 · 11 yrs 6 mos

Prairie View, TX

Plan and instruct Principles of Macroeconomics, International Trade, Economic Developmer Business Statistics, and Leadership and Ethics for undergraduate and graduate students. Manage academic spreadsheets for traditional and hybrid course offerings. Analyze studen achievement data. Utilize E-courses and other online tools to supplement instructic ... see n



Economist

Bureau of Economic Analysis

Oct 2004 – Jun 2007 · 2 yrs 9 mos

Washington D.C. Metro Area

Provided financial and operating analysis of multinational corporations in the United States. Conducted fieldwork for the collection of accounting data and assisted in the development BEA's benchmark publication. Researched and wrote report on measuring technology flows through international trade.



Senior Auditor

Industrial Bank

Sep 2003 - Aug 2004 · 1 yr

Washington D.C. Metro Area

Reviewed the reliability and integrity of financial/operating information and the means used identify, measure, and report such information. Assessed the design effectiveness of bank control procedures. Developed and executed test plans for the controls and provided recommendations for remediation of control deficiencies in specific bank functions ... see n



Bank Examiner/Summer Analyst

Federal Reserve Bank of New York May 1999 – Jul 2001 · 2 yrs 3 mos Greater New York City Area

Analyzed key financial factors such as capital adequacy, asset quality, and liquidity that indicated a bank's performance as well as compliance with banking laws and regulations. Evaluated bank's budgetary process for adherence to regulatory standards. Assessed the solvency of banks and holding companies using a fundamental risk-focused analyti ... see n

Education



Howard University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Economics 2001 – 2008

Edward Alexander Bouchet Graduate Honor Society, 2007 Howard University Graduate Assistantship for 2001 and 2002 academic years

8/28/20, 4:09 PM (1) Lawrence McNeil | LinkedIn



Columbia University in the City of New York

Master of Arts (M.A.), International Economics 1998 - 2000

Columbia University Academic Fellowship for 1998 and 1999 academic years Honors Student Delegate to the International Achievement Summit (Budapest, Hungary), 19



Morgan State University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), History 1993 - 1997

Skills & Endorsements

Economics · 18



Endorsed by 7 of Lawrence's colleagues at Prairie View A&M University

Higher Education · 17



Endorsed by Evie Myers, JD, who is highly skilled at this



Endorsed by 7 of Lawrence's colleagu Prairie View A&M University

Public Speaking · 16



Endorsed by Evie Myers, JD and 3 others who



Endorsed by 8 of Lawrence's colleagu



Q Search











Lawrence McNeil

Dean - College of Business at Bowie State Univ...

Connect





Accomplishments



Honors & Awards

Edward Alexander Bouchet Graduate Honor Society • Howard University Graduate Assistantshi 2001 and 2002 academic years • Columbia University Academic Fellowship for 1998 and 1999 academic years • Honors Student Delegate to the International Achievement Summit (Budapes Hungary) • US Fulbright Fellow • Public Policy and International Affairs Fellow

Interests



Gretchen Rubin in

Bestselling writer about habits and hap... 2,913,960 followers



Harvard Business Review

11,139,534 followers



Meg Whitman in

CEO at Quibi 2,383,464 followers



Massachusetts Institute of T

838,400 followers



CNN Business

2,977,680 followers



Howard University Alumni Gı

2,823 members

See all

Linked in

About

Accessibility

Community Guidelines

Careers

Privacy & Terms ➤

Ad Choices

Mobile

Talent Solutions

Marketing Solutions

Advertising

Small Business

Questions?
Visit our Help Ce



Safety Center

Sales Solutions

LinkedIn Corporation © 2020